Well, the talk about dividing God's land
is back again once again, and we're
going to talk about that. There's so
much to cover today. Uh, we'll also do
Clown World question of the day,
comments of the day, all the stuff we do
here daily. But I'm glad you're here. My
name is Tom, and you're watching the
Watching River channel. I hope you're
well. Today is Monday, September 14th,
2026. A beautiful day here by the river
in the middle of Connecticut. But as far
as a live studio audience goes, nobody
showed up. Nobody. No birds, no
squirrels, no cats, nothing. It's just
me and you and a dog named Boo. But uh
before we begin, I always like to go to
scripture. I'll read a couple verses,
then we'll get busy. Again, we have a
lot to cover today. Zechariah
12:es 2 and 3. Behold, I will make
Jerusalem a cup of trembling unto all
the people round about, when they shall
be in the siege both against Judah and
against Jerusalem. And in that day will
I make Jerusalem a burdensome stone for
all people. All that burden themselves
with it shall be cut in pieces, though
all the people of the earth be gathered
together against it. That day is coming
when everyone on earth turns against
Israel. Now, we're seeing a lot of it
today, but it's going to keep going and
going and going until everyone is
against Israel. Let's go to Joel 3:es 1
and 2. For behold, in those days, and in
that time, when I shall bring again the
captivity of Judah and Jerusalem, I will
also gather all nations, and will bring
them down into the valley of
Jehoshaphat,
and will plead with them there for my
people, and for my heritage, Israel,
whom they have scattered among the
nations, and parted my land."
You know, how many years have we heard
about a two-state solution so that
Israel and the Palestinians could live
in Kumbaya side by side peace? The one
problem is one side never wants peace.
When any agreement with Israel, there's
always one side that doesn't want peace.
But we have heard the eb and flow of all
the talks about the two-state solution
we have heard for so many years. But it
comes and it goes. It dies down for a
while. Well, BRICS this past weekend in
New Delhi, India, they brought it back
with a vengeance. So, listen to this.
BRIC's New Delhi declaration backs a
sovereign Palestinian state and calls
for the 1967 borders. Where have we
heard this before? The New Delhi
declaration adopted by BRICS countries
by consensus reaffirmed the block
support for a lasting two-state solution
to the Israeli Palestinian conflict and
called for stronger international
support for Palestine. The declaration
said a lasting solution can only be
achieved through peaceful means and by
protecting the rights of the Palestinian
people.
BRICS also backed Palestine's full
membership of the United Nations and
called for the establishment of a
sovereign, independent, and viable state
of Palestine within the internationally
recognized 1967 borders, including Gaza
and the West Bank with East Jerusalem as
its capital. The block said this would
help achieve the vision of two states
living side by side in peace and
security.
There's only one problem. The side
that's not Israel never wants to live
side by side in peace and security with
Israel. We know that. If you don't
understand that, go look at history
since 1948.
BRICS strongly opposed the forced
displacement of Palestinians from the
occupied Palestinian territory and
rejected any geographic or demographic
changes to Gaza. quote, "We express our
firm opposition to the force
displacement, temporary or permanent,
under any pretext of any of the
Palestinian population from the occupied
Palestinian territory, as well as any
geographic or demographic changes to the
territory of the Gaza Strip." That's
what the declaration said.
So, BRICS was just ramping up the talk.
You know, they met this past weekend in
New Delhi. That's why they're calling it
the New Delhi. It's not a New Delhi like
a a place to grab a new sandwich, you
know, like a really good sandwich. No, I
love sandwiches. But no, it's the New
Delhi India declaration because that's
where Bricks met. And then they started
this nonsense. This stuff that has been
debunked so much that it this just ends
up being complete propaganda. It's been
debunked over and over and over again.
But listen, the grouping of BRICS
nations condemned starvation as a method
of warfare. Attacks on civilians and
civilian infrastructure, including
hospitals that has been debunked so many
times they were firing missiles out of
hospital windows.
And the blocking of aid,
it reaffirmed support for ENRA, which
was proven to be infiltrated into Hamas
on October 7th, 2023.
and it pointed to provisional measures
issued by the International Court of
Justice in South Africa's case against
Israel.
These BRICS countries are so
anti-Israel. It's just un they can't
even like pretend to approach it from a
fair and balanced perspective. They
can't even pretend.
The declaration also rejected unilateral
steps to alter the legal and historical
status of occupied Jerusalem and called
for access to religious sites to be
protected.
This is such a spiritual thing. You
know, we are living in the last days.
We're waiting for Jesus to come get us
day by day. And once again, the talk of
the town, they brought it back with a
vengeance. Two-state solution. Here we
go.
And we had this uh Israel today shared
this on Telegram.
US President Donald Trump on Sunday,
yesterday, reiterated his belief that
Hamas is willing to give up its weapons
under his peace plan for the Gaza Strip.
Haven't heard that from Hamas, but
quote, "We got the hostages back." Trump
told reporters aboard Air Force One. You
know, people forget there's not a lot of
fighting in Gaza now. Hamas is now
willing to give up their weapons. End of
quote. No, they're not. They said they
might store them they over there, you
know, in a convenient in a convenient
local storage facility, you know, we'll
store them there until we want to use
them, you know. No, they're not they're
not laying down their weapons. They have
never said that.
Okay. So the bricks summit I have to
share this. The bricks summit in New
Delhi, India, they had a all the leaders
of bricks, they posed for a photo in New
Delhi. Check this out.
Look at this video. So they're all
standing there and all of a sudden Modi,
the leader of India, gets an idea. Let's
hold hands.
Check it out.
We are the world. We are the children.
[laughter] But look at the two guys all
the way to the left. They ain't holding
nobody's hand. They're like, "Ain't no
way." And then they got the little
satanic statue in the background. You
know, [laughter]
that's what happened with the bricks.
There was handholding and foods from
many lands and all kinds of things
happening there. In fact, look at this.
Chinese President Xiinping, Russian
President Putin, and Indian Prime
Minister Modi. They were seen laughing
together at the brick summit. And if you
notice once again, they're holding
hands. There was a lot of male bonding
going on this past weekend in India. You
know, a lot of hand Putin's face though
in that picture just cracked me up
because he's almost looking like what
you talk about, Willis. Why? Why do I
keep having to hold these hands?
That's just dumb humor.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Chinese President Xi offers to help
negotiate peace between the US and Iran
at the brick summit. Wow. They want to,
you know, the ones who are privately
stocking Iran with weapons and goods.
They want to help. Let's we'll help
mediate the peace between the US and
Iran. No thanks, China. No thanks.
BRICS nations call on Israel to withdraw
all troops from Lebanon.
Uh, this is a quote. We condemn the
continued violations of the ceasefire
and of the sovereignty and territorial
integrity of Lebanon. End of quote. No
mention of Hezbollah because there you
go. That's why Israel is in southern
Lebanon. It's nothing to do with the
Lebanese or the Lebanese government.
It's Hezbollah who the Lebanese
government said they would get rid of
what, almost two years ago now. Well,
there you go. I'm a little snarky today.
I apologize. Um, and then we got this
man. You remember when all those Gulf
countries were kind of running toward
Trump and and kind of leaning away from
Iran? Well, because Trump kind of
stopped the war and all of a sudden now
they're all starting to think we better
get along with Iran. But the UAE
and Iran agree to put aside their past
issues and build a future together.
And also, President Trump says he
doesn't care if Gulf nations meet with
Iran. So there you go. So right now they
seem to be, you know, kind of heading
toward Iran because they they they're
understanding, oh, there is no end to
this regime. As of right now, there's no
end.
I can't verify this, but Iran says it
shot down a US military MQ1 drone over
the Straight of Hormuz yesterday. I'm
not sure if that actually happened. I
couldn't find uh a lot of info on that.
And then President Trump is now saying
that the war with Iran could come to an
end very soon, potentially right after
the November midterm elections while
accusing Thyrron of deliberately
prolonging the conflict in an effort to
complicate the US election. Yes, seems
like that's what they're doing. But you
know what?
I personally think this is just
speculation. the best way they could
interrupt the election would be to do an
attack on Israel or whatever um for Iran
to do an attack before the election.
Maybe a few weeks before so we're up to
our ears in Middle East conflict and
then people could have enough time to
get sick of this conflict and say I'm
voting for the opposite party. I don't
know. I don't know what's going to
happen. I know one thing. Jesus is not
rattled or troubled by anything that's
going on and and I belong to him. So, I
choose to not be rattled or troubled by
this stuff. Trump continues to insist
that the central objective is preventing
Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon,
warning that the consequences of a
nuclear armed Iran would extend far
beyond the Israel and the Middle East.
There you go. Meanwhile, this conflict
continues to place enormous pressure on
global energy markets, military
stockpiles, alliances, and already
fragile world economy. Yeah, there is uh
a lot of stuff going on with with oil,
you know, with people worried about it.
Uh repairs to that Saudi Arabia East
West pipeline, they're saying, will take
far longer than a month due to a lack of
spare parts with the pumping
infrastructure catastrophically damaged
and at least eight locations on the pipe
were hit per initial reports citing
sources inside Saudi Arabia. So they
bomb that that pipeline that Saudi
Arabia had that was kind of getting
around the straight of Hormuz.
That leaves Saudi Arabia set to run out
of crude oil stocks for export within 5
to 7 days. Talking around 4 million
barrels per day, 4% of the global supply
off the market per three industry
sources to Reuters.
It's bad. The oil, I don't know if
you've tried to buy oil lately in the
stores. It's twice almost twice the
money it was a few months ago. And
Costco just put a purchase limit on its
motor oil as prices are surging. Uh for
a warehouse retailer famous for selling
items in endless bulk, imposing strict
purchasing limits is a massive red flag.
But if you plan on doing a driveway oil
change this weekend, you are in for some
severe sticker shock. Um, Costco has
officially started rationing its motor
oil to combat a rapidly deteriorating
global lubricant shortage. The days of
grabbing cheap bulk oil are over. A 10 C
box of Kirkland Signature full synthetic
motor oil, which historically retailed
for around $30, has skyrocketed to $58.
More concerningly, again, Costco has
implemented a strict two box per
customer weekly limit. Name brands
aren't fairing much better. A six court
of Mobile One is currently sitting at
$44 with purchases capped at five per
member to prevent hoarders and scalpers
from clearing the shelves.
So, Mortal Oil has gone up. Oh, there's
a squirrel over there. We now have an
official live studio audience member.
China reportedly helped Iran in the
deadly attack on US forces.
This is the same country we just said
wants to mediate between Iran and the
US. China reportedly assisted Iran with
satellite imagery ahead of a deadly
airbase attack in Jordan. Retired Navy
Captain Brent Saddler discusses the
national security fallout as President
Trump prepares to meet with President
Xiinping.
And uh that July strike that China
helped with killed three of our US
service members.
And but he wants to be the mediator
between Iran and and the US. We live in
clown world. I feel like I could use my
clown world sound effect throughout this
entire video.
The conflict in Yemen intensified
yesterday as government forces launched
attacks against Iranbacked Houthi rebels
along the Red Sea and Houthis fired into
neighboring Saudi Arabia which supports
the you know Yemen's government. The
Yemen government vowed to send more
forces to the Red Sea coast and one
official conceded a painful defeat last
week when Houthies captured the port
city of Mocha and an island on the Babel
Elm Mandde Strait, a crucial shipping
alternative to the straight of Hormuz.
So I don't see these oil energy thing
calming down anytime too soon. I think
it's actually going to get a little
worse. But we just wait for Jesus and we
trust him with everything. And then did
you hear about this?
A Russian drone struck a train near the
Ukraine Poland border yesterday on
Sunday shortly after senior visiting
officials including the former prime
ministers of the UK and Sweden they
passed through. Uh, and this was
according to Ukraine's state rail
operator. And they said former CIA
director David Petraeus was at that
Ukrainian train station when Russia
struck a passenger train. And former UK
Prime Minister Boris Johnson's train had
also passed by moments before the
strike. So pretty serious. And then
President Trump is blaming Zele Zen. I
love that. Zealy Zalinsky. He's blaming
him for the high oil prices. He said, "A
lot of diesel comes from Russia.
Russia's plants are being hit by
Ukraine." And he said, "I've asked
Zilinski not to hit the diesel plants
and the refineries." What a mess this
world is, isn't it? You know, yet there
are people who are like, "No, the
rapture is not for 50 years, 100 years,
thousand years." I just don't see it
that way. I'm waiting every day.
Here's another one. End Times Headlines
shared this. Anthropic CEO Dario Amode,
uh, one of the most influential figures
building the very technology
transforming our world, is now warning
that AI development is moving so rapidly
that the industry needs to slow down and
give safety measures time to catch up.
What happened? Other other I guess Sam
Alman also came out and said slow it
down over this weekend. And I'm thinking
with the release of Astra and they've
got Claude, it's like what's what did
they see that spooked them or something?
Something went on because all of a
sudden over the weekend they're like we
got to slow this down. It's like hm what
happened? What's happening? A Moday
warns that increasingly autonomous and
self-improving AI systems could
eventually outrun humanity's ability to
understand or control them. even
suggesting that within 6 to 12 months, a
sufficiently capable swarm of rogue AI
agents could potentially wreak havoc
across the internet.
Nobody will care until Tik Tok shut down
or something, you know, then they'll
freak out. Then the whole world will
freak out.
According to a report from the
Washington Post, President Trump on
Sunday dismissed calls from leading art
artificial intelligence executives to
slow the race for more powerful models,
arguing that the United States cannot
afford to lose its lead over China. So
all of this is all about, you know, we
got to win this. We got to win this AI
arms race. You know,
this is interesting. I saw this in
insider paper.
The leaders of Scotland, Wales, and
Northern Ireland have reportedly met in
Cardiff, and signed a joint declaration
seeking independence from the UK, the
United Kingdom. The declaration invokes
each nation's right to
self-determination and demands the right
to hold referendums for independence.
Wow. The meeting marks a significant
moment in history as it's the first time
since devolution that pro-independence
factions are simultaneously in the
majority across all three nations. So
all three of those nations are saying we
want to get out of this United Kingdom.
I mean this we're living in amazing
times.
Did you hear about this? A 3,000mi cloud
of Saharin dust headed towards Florida.
Yeah, it's a 3,000mi dust cloud near
Africa. It's heading across the Atlantic
towards Florida. It's unusual timing for
the Saharan Desert as these dust storms
usually thin out by September. And
they're saying the Saharan dust usually
reduces the risk of tropical storm
development. But that's heading toward
Florida. We'll see what happens there.
And then we got a lot of earthquakes.
Not powerful ones, little ones, but a
lot of them in California. A swarm of
small earthquakes rattled parts of
Southern California from Friday night
into Saturday with activity concentrated
from Lennox and West Mount. The US
Geological Survey defines an earthquake
swarm as a series of earthquakes that
occur in a relative relatively small
area over a period of time. Unlike a
typical earthquake sequence, a swarm
does not have a defined main shock
followed by aftershocks.
But yeah, they said there was a lot of
them. There was over they said according
to the USGS, dozens of earthquakes
occurred over a span of just 18 hours
between 8:00 p.m. Friday and 2:30 p.m.
Saturday. And they range from 1.0 to
2.7. So they were very low, but there
was quite a few. The last 48 hours
overall earthquakes I would say were
down 75 over 4.0 and 25 over 5.0.
So there you go. Now it is time.
Get your thinking caps on. It's time for
the question of the day.
What's your favorite Bible story? Now I
don't like to say Bible story, so I'll
say what's your favorite Bible event in
the entire word of God? What's your
favorite Bible event that happened?
I'm not going to give my answer right
now. Maybe tomorrow I will because I do
have a favorite. But that's the question
of the day. So, how's about Now we go
on. This is so clowny, guys. We're going
to clown world. And this one is just
all before I even read it, all I can
think of is no thanks. I'll just have
water. But listen to this. Dyson debuts
a $499
AI powered toothbrush with a built-in
camera. [laughter]
Dyson has introduced this $499
toothbrush that uses artificial
intelligence. It's got a built-in camera
and it gives real time feedback. I I
just want to brush my teeth. I just want
to brush my teeth. Leave me alone. The
latest in a growing subset of gadgets
that put AI and video in sometimes
unconventional places.
Smart toothbrushes are hardly new.
Companies such as OralB and Phillips
offer models that work with an app to
track coverage, pressure, brushing time,
and other user data. But Dyson said its
new camera jet model is the first with
an integrated camera to hone in on the
spaces between the teeth where plaque
first forms then hardens and direct a
precision jet at them. The product is
being offered in blue and pink. For
$499, it better be me a lot more colors
and features. The product launch follows
a broader push by consumer tech
companies to normalize the presence of
cameras and devices that didn't
traditionally have them, including
eyeglasses, headphones, and pendants.
That's it, guys. AI is heading into our
mouths now. You know, it's like
[laughter]
a camera is brushing my teeth.
Clown world.
I'm picturing the the camera inside my
mouth. Hey, there's the tongue. There's
the guy's tongue. Hey, where did his
tonsils go? Get out of my mouth. I just
want to brush my teeth.
Clown world. You got Would you guys
anybody out there? Somebody would.
Somebody's going to say they would.
Would you spend 500 bucks on a
toothbrush so a camera could look
between your teeth? I just, you know,
the floss goes between my teeth. I don't
need a camera there. I'm fine. All
right. It's clown world.
All right. How's about we read a few
comments of the day, shall we? See if I
can find them.
Doug, we are living in uncharted and
uncertain times. God is the one to hold
on to. In these times, come to the Lord
if you are weary and burdened and he
will give you rest. Amen. And Doug, I
say, "Amen." Beautiful. Thank you,
Tom Phillips.
I'm planning to play a trombone solo at
church tomorrow. If the Lord would like
to join me with a solid trumpet blast
during my solo, I wouldn't object at
all. I love that, Tom. Amen. Amen.
Suz,
the only way to be ready for what is
happening is to believe that the Lord
Jesus shed his precious blood on the
cross for our sins to be forgiven. There
is no other way. Happy Rashashana, she
said. Amen. Thank you sis. Thank you.
And it is still Rashashana in case you
the the sliver of the moon was seen on
Saturday night. So it's about a 48 hour
thing. So tonight Israel time will be
the end of Rashashana according to
if it's not a month off because some
people are already saying they've said
for a long time the calendars that they
use in Israel are a month off. I don't
know.
Allison,
uh, my question of the day on Saturday
was, "Do you guys like memorizing
scripture? Can you do it? Is it hard for
you?" And Allison said, "I'm terrible at
memorizing scripture." I could when I
was a kid because I was forced to. I
would recite it in order to earn a badge
and then I would forget it. Now I can
understand and explain passages of
scripture, but it doesn't seem to stick
if I try to memorize it. I'm the same
way. I have a hard time. I if I repeat a
verse over and over and over and over
and over, it can get in my head and I
can finish it if somebody starts it. But
remembering what chapter and verse and
I've just always and it gets worse with
age, you know, I got to a point I was a
singer and songwriter for years. I wrote
over 300 songs and I still write songs
for watching River Music, but I wrote a
lot of songs and I got to an age I think
in my mid4s where someone said I had a
guitar and someone would say, "Oh, play
that song that you wrote." and they'd
name some song and I'd be like start
singing it and it's like too long. I'm
like I don't remember the lyrics. Like
but you wrote the song. It's like I just
don't remember the lyrics.
Anyway,
Kevin,
I love your posts. They encourage me to
be ready and about the master's business
until he calls us home. I'll look you up
in heaven after the rapture. Amen,
Kevin. I'll look you up, too. I can't
wait to see everyone up there,
especially Jesus first and foremost,
obviously. But one day soon, can you
imagine? We're going to gather at the
feet of the master of creation, at the
feet of Jesus. We're going to gather
there, all of us together, the perfect
body of Christ with Jesus as the head. I
just can't wait for that day. I can't
wait for that day. Can you imagine what
that's going to be like to be in the
immediate family of God where nobody's
backbiting or or talking bad about each
other? It will just be love. And I mean,
I don't know how many I don't know,
billions. I don't know, but billions of
brothers and sisters sitting at the feet
of Jesus. I just can't imagine. I'm so
excited for it. I think you guys know
that. And I happen to believe the
rapture is soon, you know. But you know
what? If you don't know Jesus, you have
to hear the gospel because time is
short. And it's a very important
decision you have to make at the end of
this talk I'm about to have. You have to
make a decision and it's the most
important decision of your entire life.
You see, we all needed a rescue because
we're all sinners. We all fall short of
the glory of God. We miss the mark.
We're not perfect by far. And the only
way that sin can be paid for is by the
shedding of blood. Without the shedding
of blood, there is no remission of sin
according to Hebrews 9:22. Blood has to
be shed. So, in the Old Testament, they
took the animals and they slaughtered
them and they sprinkled the blood in the
Holy of Holies and their sins were
covered for a year. Well, then Jesus
came along 2,000 years ago, born of a
virgin, conceived by the Holy Spirit.
And Jesus left heaven to come here to
die for our sins, to pay for them with
his blood. That's why he came here. He
did amazing things. He loved on people.
He did miracles and healings and
teaching. Amazing. He came here to die
on that cross for you.
Can you get a grip of that? That is so
incredible to me that the most high God
sent his only begotten son that so
whoever believes in him should not
perish but have everlasting life. God
doesn't want anyone to go to hell. Hell
wasn't created for mankind. It was
created for Satan and his angels. God
provided his only begotten son to die on
a cross. Jesus was absolutely perfect.
He never sinned once and he went to that
cross to pay for our sins with his
blood. God doesn't want anyone to go to
hell. He wants all to believe in Jesus.
But if you hear this and you're like,
"Well, I just don't want this. I don't
want to have to believe in it." You're
rejecting a payment that was made. The
lamb of God, Jesus, made a blood payment
and you're saying, "Well, I don't need
that." And so many people, the famous,
most famous one is, "Why do you think
you're getting to heaven?" Well, I I'm a
pretty good person. I'm more good than
bad. It's like you can't earn your way
into heaven by your goodness. Heaven is
more perfect than we can comprehend.
You need a payment for your sins. And
God sent Jesus to provide that payment,
a blood payment, a very serious payment.
And all you have to do to be saved is
you have to admit you're a sinner. You
have to understand you need payment for
the sins you've committed and will
commit in your lifetime. And you say,
"Jesus, I admit I'm a sinner. I know I'm
a sinner. I think weird things and I've
done things I'm ashamed of. I am a
sinner and I now believe that you came
here from heaven to shed your blood to
wash me white as snow. So, I'm having
faith in your blood that you shed that
my sin problem will be washed away and I
will be washed white as snow. And that's
what happens. And you say, "Jesus, I
believe in your finished work on the
cross. You were nailed to the cross and
you shed that precious blood and you
died and you were buried and you rose
again the third day. I need a savior,
Jesus. and I now realize you are the one
and only savior. There is no other way
to heaven. It's Jesus or nothing. It's
either forever with Jesus or forever
separated from Jesus. No other major
religious figure ever said what Jesus
did. Jesus said, "I am the way, the
truth, and the life. No one gets to the
father except through me." It's the one
path to heaven is Jesus. There's no
other path. There's nothing else coming
along. So that leads you to the greatest
decision of your entire life. Are you
going to say yes to that? Are you going
to say, "No, I don't want that."
You know, you don't want to face Jesus
on judgment day and be led off to
eternal separation from God because you
just never ever believed. You know,
horrible. I wouldn't wish that my worst
enemy, honestly. But in my prayer time
this morning, I said a prayer for every
single person who would watch this
video. So, like it or not, you have been
prayed for today. And if we're not
raptured today, and I think today's a
perfectly good day for the rapture, but
if not, God willing, I will see you guys
tomorrow. I love you guys. [music]
>> Oh, Jesus,
Savior, [music]
master,
creator,
you're the alpha. [music]
Omega,
you're the King of Kings.